Captain Zhao and the others arrested a CCP member
赵队长等人抓捕一名中共党员
died
死了
Let me transport it out and throw it away
让我把它运出去扔掉
Tragic
悲惨
two knives
两把刀
what happened again
又发生了什么事
etc.
ETC。
do you know
你知道吗
Under the scorching sun
烈日下
Yang Qi prevails
杨奇占上风
Ghosts will not find their way to the underworld
鬼魂不会找到通往阴间的路
What does it have to do with me that he can't find a way?
他找不到办法与我有什么关系？
Of course it has something to do with you
当然跟你有关系
He can't find the way
他找不到路
They will pester the person who moved the body.
他们会纠缠搬动尸体的人。
Especially an innocent ghost like this who died tragically
尤其是像这样一个无辜的鬼魂却惨死
When the time comes, you won’t be able to get rid of me even if you want to.
到时候，你就算想摆脱我，也摆脱不了我。
real
真实的
So what should I do?
所以我该怎么做？
You put a coin in his mouth
你把一枚硬币放进他嘴里
If you have money, you can ask for directions.
有钱的话可以问路。
Makes sense
说得通
Thanks
谢谢
This one
这个
It was given to me by the comrades who came from Yan'an today.
这是今天从延安来的同志送给我的。
old road
老路
Tomorrow morning
明天早上
I will talk to several people in charge of the intelligence station
我会和情报站的几个负责人谈谈
A meeting was held at Haibanxian Tea House to discuss this matter
海板仙茶馆召开会议讨论此事
You should pay close attention tomorrow
明天你要密切关注
What’s going on at the trading house and the military police headquarters?
贸易行和宪兵司令部到底发生了什么？
Carry out perimeter security work
做好周边安保工作
boarding
登机
Walk
走
How many bosses are you?
你们是几个老板？
I made an appointment with a friend to talk about something in the private room upstairs
我约了朋友去楼上包间谈点事情
Okay, please come in
好的，请进来
Boss Lu
卢老板
I've finally found you
我终于找到你了
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
why are you here
你为什么在这
come over
过来
We met Chen Jiaping at the calligraphy and painting shop.
我们在字画店遇见了陈家平。
Then I followed him here.
然后我就跟着他来到了这里。
team leader
队长
Do you want to rush in right now?
你想现在就冲进去吗？
Arrest Lao Lu and his accomplices
抓捕老鲁及其同伙
The old path is the Communist Party
老路是共产党
But meeting him for tea
但遇见他喝茶
Not necessarily a communist
不一定是共产主义者
If you act rashly
如果你鲁莽行事
All the hard work is in vain.
所有的努力都是徒劳的。
The clues are gone
线索消失了
The inkstone you sold me was actually a fake
你卖给我的砚台其实是假的
And closed the store
并且关店了
What's wrong
怎么了
Are you afraid that I will find you?
你害怕我会找到你吗？
Mr. Chen
陈先生
What do I do for an inkstone?
我要砚台做什么？
I have something to do today
我今天有事要做
I made an appointment with a few friends to talk up there.
我约了几个朋友去那里谈谈。
All right
好的
I'll go up first
我先上去
It's okay to talk
说话没事
what are you doing
你在干什么
There seems to be something wrong over there on the old road.
老路上的那条路似乎有些不对劲。
Should we evacuate?
我们应该撤离吗？
There's a spy at the door
门口有间谍
Destroy files immediately
立即销毁文件
Kobeko Agawa
阿川神户子 - 最好的阿川神户子
You will go to the teahouse in a moment
一会儿你就去茶馆了
Optimistic about the old road
看好老路
Where exactly?
具体在哪里？
There are also several people who met
还有几个认识的人
team leader
队长
Out
出去
You give me the money for the inkstone
你给我买砚台的钱
Let’s talk however we want
让我们随心所欲地谈论
Not Mr. Chen
不是陈先生
I don’t have that much money with me now.
我现在身上没有那么多钱。
no problem
没问题
You go in my car
你坐我的车去
Go to your store and get money
去你的商店拿钱
Not your car
不是你的车
yes
是的
Mr. Chen
陈先生
You are also my regular customer
你也是我的常客
There is some basic trust between us
我们之间有一些基本的信任
All gone
全没了
seems to be quarreling
好像在吵架
Chen Jiaping knew that the old road was exposed
陈家平知道旧路暴露
He is here to save Lao Lu
他是来救老鲁的
Now you are a cunning old man
现在你是个狡猾的老头了
Hurry up and don't say anything
快点，什么也别说
boarding
登机
take the money
拿钱
Why are you like this?
你为什么这样？
team leader
队长
If you don't take action, it will be too late.
如果你不采取行动，那就太晚了。
Maybe it's to lure the tiger away from the mountain
也许是为了引虎离山
Want to lure us away
想把我们引走
do not forget
不要忘记
There are communists in the teahouse
茶馆里有共产党员
They want the communists to
他们希望共产党人
Have a chance to escape
有机会逃脱
trunk
树干
How many people can you take to follow Chen Jiaping and Lao Lu?
你能带多少人去追随陈家平和老鲁？
yes
是的
Agawa Kazukobeiko
阿川和子兵兵卫
Come with me
跟我来
Are you sure about the comrade who died?
你确定死去的同志吗？
Smoking big leaf tobacco
抽大叶烟草
That's right
这是正确的
your joint
你的关节
They are all under Zhao An's surveillance
他们都在赵安的监视之下
Your identity has been exposed now
你的身份现在已经暴露了
The reason why I didn’t arrest you right away
我之所以没有立即逮捕你
I want you to attract more comrades
我希望你能吸引更多的同志
Are you from Zhao An?
你是赵安人吗？
right
正确的
Lure them away first
先把他们引走
Hurry up
赶快
follow him
跟着他
Follow, follow, follow
关注，关注，关注
old road
老路
you have to leave shanghai
你必须离开上海
But I'm leaving
但我要离开了
Your identity is exposed
你的身份暴露了
I
我
I'm just you
我只是你
Frequent customer of calligraphy and painting shop
字画店常客
I bought a fake inkstone
我买了一块假砚台
Just happened to bump into you
刚好碰见你
Looking for your theory
寻找你的理论
I want you to return the money to me
我要你把钱还给我
this drama
这部剧
I can still continue to act in this play
这部戏我还能继续演
But you didn’t follow me back to the calligraphy and painting shop
可你却没有跟着我回字画店
I suddenly disappeared
我突然消失了
how do you explain
你怎么解释
You arrived at the teahouse
你到了茶馆
Found someone following you
发现有人关注你
I appeared when I was at a loss
在我失落的时候我出现了
You took the opportunity to leave the teahouse with me
你趁机跟我一起离开茶馆
The most I can do is be used by you
我最多能做的就是被你利用
Far-fetched
牵强附会
Too far-fetched
太牵强
Luo Guanqun
Luo Guanqun
I'm afraid in the future
我害怕在未来
I won't trust you anymore
我不会再相信你了
Let’s talk about what happens next.
我们来谈谈接下来会发生什么。
ok
好的
There is a steamed stuffed bun shop in front of this intersection.
这个路口前面有一家包子店。
I know the boss there
我认识那里的老板
He can vouch for me
他可以为我作担保
I put you down there
我把你放在那里
Which private room was the person we had an argument with just now was in?
刚才和我们吵架的人在哪个包间？
I don't know either
我也不知道
He just went up the stairs
他刚上楼梯
I was stopped by another guest.
我被另一位客人拦住了。
The two talked for a while
两人聊了一会儿
It started quarreling
就开始吵架了
Are all your private rooms upstairs?
你们的私人房间都在楼上吗？
yes
是的
I mean Boss Lu
我是说陆老板
Why did you ask me to stop here?
你为什么要我停在这里？
Why don't you go to your store?
你为什么不去你的商店？
Not Mr. Chen
不是陈先生
You lose such a temper
你就这么发脾气
You want to come to my store
你想来我的店
How do I do this business?
我该如何做这个生意？
You think about your business now
你现在考虑你的生意
When you sold me a fake inkstone
当你卖给我一块假砚台时
Why don't you want to
你为什么不想
Boss Cao, let me ask you
曹老板，我问你一下
If someone eats something bad at your place
如果有人在你家吃了不好的东西
Do you pay or not?
你付钱还是不付钱？
I'll definitely have to pay for it.
我肯定要付出代价。
Did you look at it?
你看过吗？
lose money
赔钱
Come
来
Mr. Chen Mr. Chen
陈先生 陈先生
help
帮助
Don't go to my store
不要去我的商店
I promise
我保证
I'll go to the store immediately and get the money
我马上去商店取钱
Sent to you
寄给你
Where can you find me?
你在哪里可以找到我？
where you work
你在哪里工作
I I know
我知道
I've been there
我去过那儿
I mean Boss Lu
我是说陆老板
Stop playing tricks on me
别再捉弄我了
I promise I promise
我保证我保证
rest assured
放心
Mr. Chen
陈先生
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Nothing
没有什么
Sell ​​me a fake inkstone
卖给我一块假砚台
How is business?
生意如何？
so-so
一般般
How many private rooms are there in total?
共有多少间私人房间？
Twelve private rooms in total
共有十二间私人房间
Are all seats full?
所有座位都满了吗？
All eight rooms have guests.
所有八个房间都有客人。
There are private rooms on both sides
两边都有包房
Smells of smoke
闻起来有烟味
A guest smokes
有客人抽烟
very normal
很正常
Not the smell of cigarette smoke
不是香烟的味道
Yeah
是的
Received yet
尚未收到
Like it
喜欢它
Su Jin's
Su Jin's
Miss
错过
can you hurry up
你能快点吗
I'm in a hurry
我很急
you are in a hurry
你很着急
I have something urgent to do
我有紧急事要做
good
好的
Then I'll hang up first
那我先挂了
There is something else to do today
今天还有事要做
Thanks
谢谢
I'll leave it to you at home.
我把它留给你在家里。
Please be sure to contact your fourth brother
请务必联系你的四哥
OK
好的
goodbye
再见
stop
停止
Don't run
别跑
Caught alive
活捉
Chase
追赶
Slow down
减速
You go over there and chase
你去那里追
I go this way
我走这条路
yes
是的
old road
老路
Go quickly, go quickly
快点走快点
You can't run away
你无法逃跑
take away
带走
Stand together in the same box
一起站在同一个盒子里
Stand ready
做好准备
team leader
队长
Where is the old road?
旧路在哪里？
Got it
知道了
Not caught either
也没抓到
what does it mean
这是什么意思
Caught
捕捉
But it wasn't our people who caught him
但抓到他的不是我们的人
who caught
谁抓住了
large spoon
大勺子
I was about to catch someone
我正要抓住一个人
As a result, Damasao suddenly appeared halfway.
结果，大马骚突然出现在半路上。
Take away the old road
带走旧路
Why is he following the old path?
他为何还要走老路？
He said he found out that Lao Lu was a communist
他说他发现老鲁是共产党员
How could he know about Lao Lu?
他怎么会知道老鲁的事？
this
这
I don't know either
我也不知道
Where is Chen Jiaping?
陈家平在哪里？
Lost a section in the middle
中间丢了一段
Later, when we met the old road again,
后来，当我们再次遇见那条老路时，
Chen Jiaping has disappeared
陈家平失踪了
I really didn't expect it
我真的没想到
My pen, ink, paper and inkstone
我的笔墨纸砚
It turned out to be provided by a Communist Party member.
原来是一名共产党员提供的。
These are all good things
这些都是好东西
It's just in your hands
就在你的手中
What I drew was artificial.
我画的东西是人造的。
Flattery trash
奉承垃圾
Really like the painting
真的很喜欢画
What a pity
真可惜
stop wasting time
别再浪费时间了
do your tricks
做你的把戏
torture
酷刑
Use them all
全部使用它们
let's start
开始吧
Mr. Lu is a cultural person
卢先生是一位文化人
I wouldn't do that to you
我不会那样对你
Meat that has been stewed for so many days
炖了这么多天的肉
stewed
炖
I can smell the meaty aroma
我能闻到肉香
The meat is gone
肉没了
team leader
队长
What should we do now
我们现在应该做什么
The old road lies in Luo Guanqun's hands
老路在罗冠群手中
once confessed
一旦表白
Communists in the teahouse
茶馆里的共产党人
They will take it away in one fell swoop
他们会一举拿走
Before we confess
在我们坦白之前
Uncover these communist parties
揭露这些共产党
This is our last hope
这是我们最后的希望
yes
是的
what did you find
你发现了什么
good
好的
I see
我懂了
We went to Yumo calligraphy and painting shop
我们去了玉墨字画店
Just rummage and find it
只需翻阅并找到它
Someone likes it
有人喜欢
I send you
我送你
I really found what I like
我真的找到了我喜欢的东西
That's my Huanhua paper
这是我的浣花纸
Or Longxiang Yumo?
Or Longxiang Yumo?
Not to mention
更何况
None of these are what I like.
这些都不是我喜欢的。
All of us are here to drink tea.
我们大家都是来喝茶的。
Why are you drinking?
你为什么喝酒？
It's against the law to drink too much
饮酒过量是违法的
That's right
这是正确的
I didn’t let you speak, so I shut my mouth.
我不让你说话，所以我闭嘴了。
Don't shut up
别闭嘴
Let you add more sin to sin
让你罪上加罪
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Tea patrons in the eight private rooms on the second floor
二楼八个包房里的茶客
It's all here
一切都在这里
Have you checked everything?
你检查过一切吗？
Checked
已检查
I also searched them one by one.
我也一一搜索了。
No clues found
没有找到任何线索
The Communist Party is among you
共产党就在你们中间
Let me tell you the truth
让我告诉你真相
Lao Lu has been arrested by us
老鲁被我们抓了
who are his accomplices
谁是他的同伙
Take the initiative to stand up
主动站起来
I'm giving you a chance to confess your own sins.
我给你一个机会承认你自己的罪孽。
Take the initiative to plead guilty
主动认罪
We will forget about it
我们会忘记它
You guys think clearly
你们想清楚了
Even if you don’t admit it now
就算你现在不承认
old road
老路
Will confess soon
很快就会表白
And come and identify you
并过来认出你
stand out
脱颖而出
You just checked
您刚刚检查过
Who do you think is the most suspect?
你认为谁的嫌疑最大？
these two
这两个
I just wanted to jump out of the window and escape
我只想跳出窗外逃走
why run away
为什么要逃跑
us
我们
You are waiting for the old road
你在等老路
You are a communist
你是共产主义者
no
不
What an old road
多么古老的路
We don't even know this person
我们甚至不认识这个人
Why run away
为什么要逃跑
Xiaolan
小兰
Secretary
秘书
Let me tell you the truth
让我告诉你真相
I
我
I am a married man
我是已婚男人
She is a married woman
她是一个已婚妇女
We secretly came out to meet each other.
我们偷偷出来见面。
As for what you are looking for
至于你在寻找什么
We don't know either
我们也不知道
We are afraid of being discovered by others
我们害怕被别人发现
So we have to jump out of the window and escape.
所以我们只能从窗户跳出去逃走。
you are lying
你在说谎
You are the Communist Party
你是共产党
I swear
我发誓
I'm really not
我真的不是
Secretary
秘书
You can't accuse me wrongly
你不能错误地指责我
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
There are clues
有线索
explain
解释
I just discovered that there are three tea guests in Haiyue Hall
我这才发现海月堂里来了三个茶客
But they asked for four tea sets
但他们要了四套茶具
Haiyue Hall
Haiyue Hall
Yes
是的
People from Haiyue Hall
海月堂的人
Who is the person in the private room of Haiyue Hall?
海月殿包间里的人是谁？
Who is from Haiyue Hall?
海月堂的人是谁？
Let me ask one last question
让我问最后一个问题
Who is the guest of Haiyue Hall?
海月堂的客人是谁？
stand out
脱颖而出
How many of us are
我们有多少人
You are a communist
你是共产主义者
You are waiting for the old road
你在等老路
we are waiting for a friend
我们正在等一位朋友
His name is Guan Dajiang
His name is Guan Dajiang
He's a fur trader
他是一个毛皮商人
You are just waiting for the old road
你只是在等待旧路
You are the Communist Party
你是共产党
We are really not the Communist Party
我们真的不是共产党
Secretary
秘书
You need to have evidence for what you say.
你所说的话需要有证据。
it's him
是他
He is Guan Dajiang
He is Guan Dajiang
who are you
你是谁
I'm in the fur business
我是做毛皮生意的
I made an appointment with some colleagues today
今天我和一些同事约好了
Come over for tea and chat
过来喝茶聊天
I was temporarily delayed because of something else.
我因为别的事暂时耽搁了。
Come a little late
来得有点晚
I saw a closing sign hanging outside.
我看到外面挂着一个关门的牌子。
I just said come in and see what's going on.
我只是说进来看看发生了什么事。
you lied
你撒谎
You are a communist
你是共产主义者
I'm in the fur business
我是做毛皮生意的
you are all lying
你们都在撒谎
You are all communists
你们都是共产主义者
Secretary
秘书
My store is at No. 355 Daxi Road
我的店在大西路355号
If you don’t believe it, you can check it out.
不信的话你可以去看看。
Check it out
一探究竟
You are all communists
你们都是共产主义者
Brother, calm down
兄弟冷静点
what are you doing
你在干什么
Luo Guanqun is racing with me
罗冠群跟我赛跑
I can't lose
我不能输
check
查看
elder brother
哥哥
I figured out a way
我想出了一个办法
I have a way
我有办法
Mr. Lu is really rigorous in his work.
卢先生做事确实很严谨。
Didn't give us any clues
没有给我们任何线索
But it’s a matter of distance.
但这是一个距离问题。
These documents reveal your secret
这些文件泄露了你的秘密
we investigated
我们调查了
you live alone
你独自生活
Food and accommodation are all in the store
吃住行都在店里
But
但
You bring some daily necessities
你带一些日常用品
Send to this address
发送至此地址
what do you want to say
你想说什么
you have family
你有家庭
Because of your work and tasks
因为你的工作和任务
Are you afraid of causing trouble to your family?
你不怕给家人带来麻烦吗？
You care about them silently
你默默地关心着他们
So you send all these things to them
所以你把所有这些东西发送给他们
i have no family
我没有家人
No. 78 Luban Road
鲁班路78号
Very easy to find
很容易找到
What do you want to do
你想让我做什么
this
这
A pair of tiger head cotton shoes
虎头棉鞋一双
Half a catty of sweet-scented osmanthus sugar cake
半斤桂花糖糕
There is also a toy car
还有一辆玩具车
These are all for children, right?
这些都是给小孩子的吧？
How old is the child?
孩子多大了？
cute
可爱的
Don't touch them
不要碰它们
they are innocent
他们是无辜的
good
好的
Then let’s go back to the previous topic
那么我们回到之前的话题
Are you still saying nothing?
你还在说什么吗？
Have you thought it through?
你想清楚了吗？
Stretch out your hands
伸出你的双手
Why are you shaking?
你为什么发抖？
Why are there burnt colors on your fingers?
为什么手指上有烧焦的颜色？
I smoked for twenty years
我抽烟了二十年
This finger is yellowed
这个手指发黄了
It's normal
这是正常的
wrong
错误的
Not the smell of smoking
不是烟味
Did you burn the file?
你烧文件了吗？
No
不
I've been drinking tea
我一直在喝茶
I'll ask you one last time
我最后一次再问你一次
Are you a communist?
你是共产主义者吗？
This officer
这位官员
You say that everyone you meet is a communist without any evidence.
你说你遇到的每个人都是共产党员，没有任何证据。
Which unit do you belong to?
你是哪个单位的？
This is your idea
这是你的想法
very nice
很不错
Which unit?
哪个单位？
We are the Military Police Headquarters
我们是宪兵司令部
Specifically to catch you Communists
专门抓你们共产党人
OK
好的
Take me to the Military Police Headquarters
带我去宪兵司令部
Do you think I dare not?
你以为我不敢吗？
Bring back
带回
torture
酷刑
yes
是的
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
Busy now
现在很忙
Why is Manager Luo here?
洛经理怎么来了？
I heard you caught the Communists
我听说你抓到了共产党
Let me take a look
让我看一看
right
正确的
Checking
检查
Found out immediately
立即发现
Got a clue
有线索了
he he he
呵呵呵呵
All suspected
全部被怀疑
Do you doubt this gentleman?
你怀疑这位先生吗？
I have evidence
我有证据
do you know who he is
你知道他是谁吗
Boss Cheng
Boss Cheng
An irresistible friend of the boss
老板不可抗拒的朋友
Controls half of Shanghai's cotton yarn business
控制上海棉纱业务半壁江山
gendarmerie headquarters
宪兵总部
All treated as honored guests
所有人都被视为尊贵的客人
Always behave in a low-key manner
行事始终低调
You said he is the Chinese Communist Party
你说他是中国共产党
This commander is too unreasonable.
这指挥官也太不讲理了。
I couldn't help but call Boss Cheng.
我忍不住给程老板打电话。
Excuse me
打扰一下
I'm blind
我瞎了
I am here to investigate the communists
我是来调查共产党的
How about this
这个怎么样
You do it in front of Boss Cheng
你当着程总的面做
Slap yourself ten times
打自己十个耳光
Forget it
忘了它
how
如何
Don't want to fight
不想打架
Then I'll call Kimura.
那我就给木村打电话。
Give a review to Boss Cheng
给程老板点评一下
satisfied
使满意
Boss Cheng
Boss Cheng
I'm talking to a friend about something private
我正在和朋友谈论一些私人的事情
Unable to identify myself
无法识别自己的身份
No wonder this brother
难怪这位兄弟
Boss Cheng
Boss Cheng
Your Excellency a lot
阁下多多
Can we go then?
那我们可以走了吗？
certainly
当然
Come
来
Boss Cheng is wronged
程老板受委屈了
open the door
打开门
Let all these people go
让这些人都走
Can't let go
无法放手
Continue to check
继续检查
No need for you to check
不需要你检查
Which two
哪两个
It's from Dongli Hall
来自东丽堂
Shopkeeper
店主
these two
这两个
large spoon
大勺子
Take these two people away from me
把这两个人从我身边带走
They are the Chinese Communist Party
他们是中国共产党
No
不
We are not the CCP
我们不是中共
not us
不是我们
right
正确的
you made a mistake
你犯了一个错误
It's really not us
确实不是我们
We are not the Communist Party
我们不是共产党
Catch
抓住
yes
是的
take away
带走
You are mistaken
你误会了
Wrong arrest
错误逮捕
It's really not us
确实不是我们
Got it wrong
搞错了
You are mistaken
你误会了
It's really not us
确实不是我们
Secretary
秘书
How do you know they are the Chinese Communist Party?
你怎么知道他们是中国共产党？
how could I know
我怎么知道
Do I need to tell you?
需要我告诉你吗？
The old road is the goal I have been following for a long time
老路是我长久以来追寻的目标
Even if you catch him
就算你抓住了他
this case
这个案例
The two of us are working together, right?
我们两个正在一起工作，对吗？
You work in the stable
你在马厩工作
What should I cooperate with you for?
我该和你合作什么？
Captain Zhao
Captain Zhao
There's always something wrong with you
你总是有问题
Always touch things you shouldn't touch
总是触碰不该触碰的东西
What a stinky problem
多么臭的问题
team leader
队长
the rest of these people
其余的人
return
返回
All recruited
全部招募
One is named Chen Shaoxiong
一个叫陈劭雄
One is named Bai Yao
一个叫白耀
At first, I kept insisting that
起初我一直坚持
He is a cigarette dealer
他是一名香烟贩子
Then gave them some torture
然后给了他们一些折磨
Just recruit it
就招募吧
I thought the Communist Party was so powerful
我以为共产党这么强大
This is not
这不是
It’s also fleshy
也是肉肉的
I also know it hurts
我也知道很痛
Have you breathed your last?
你咽下最后一口气了吗？
Haven't breathed out yet
还没出气
He must have fainted
他一定是晕倒了
This is okay
这没关系
You ask him
你问他
Chen Shaoxiong
Chen Shaoxiong
Are you a communist?
你是共产主义者吗？
do not hit me
不要打我
I said
我说
I am a communist
我是一名共产主义者
Do you know the old road?
你知道那条老路吗？
know
知道
What are you doing at Haibanxian Teahouse?
你在海半仙茶馆做什么？
meeting
会议
What meeting?
什么会议？
What content
什么内容
I open
我打开
Let me go, let me go
让我走，让我走
louder
更响亮
A bit harsh
有点严厉
Let him slow down
让他慢下来
Anyway, we have the people in our hands
无论如何，人都在我们手里
Recruited them all too
也把他们都招进来了
Review slowly
慢慢复习
I always feel that there is something wrong with those two CCP
我总觉得那两个CCP有问题
Will not
将不会
Lao Lu personally confessed
老鲁亲口承认
They met in that Dongli Hall
他们相遇在那个东丽殿
And he knows it very well
他很清楚这一点
If you lied to me
如果你对我撒谎
His family is dead.
他的家人都死了。
Manager Luo
Manager Luo
I'll go down and take a look
我下去看看
Go, go, go
去！去！去
go away
离开
uncle
叔叔
please
请
give some money
给一些钱
let me take a sip
让我喝一口
Let me take a sip, uncle
让我喝一口，叔叔
Please, sir
先生，请
Give me some money and let me take a sip
给我一些钱，让我喝一口
Just one bite
只需咬一口
boarding
登机
Give me some money, sir
先生，给我一些钱吧
Just one bite
只需咬一口
uncle
叔叔
Where to go boss?
老板去哪里？
Back to the interrogation room
回到审讯室
good
好的
Just one bite
只需咬一口
Passed this intersection
过了这个路口
There is a bun shop in front
前面有一家包子店
I know the boss there
我认识那里的老板
He can vouch for me
他可以为我作担保
I put you down there
我把你放在那里
what's on your mind
你在想什么
have you ever thought about
你有没有想过
Zhao An already knows my identity
赵安已经知道我的身份了
There is no way he would let it go
他不可能放手
Those comrades who want to meet me
那些想见我的战友
When I stopped you at the teahouse
当我在茶馆拦住你的时候
You haven't met them yet
你还没见过他们
So Zhao An temporarily
所以赵安暂时
Can't find which box it is from
找不到它来自哪个盒子
Based on your understanding of Zhao An, what would he do?
以你对赵安的了解，他会做什么？
Search all the private rooms on the second floor
搜查二楼所有包间
But just now
但就在现在
We were making a lot of noise at the top of the stairs
我们在楼梯顶上发出很大的噪音
It is also a warning to comrades
也是给战友们的一个警示
I believe they will take action
我相信他们会采取行动
And destroy important documents together
并一起销毁重要文件
Zhao An will never give up.
赵安永远不会放弃。
He will bite him to death
他会咬死他
Even at the expense of hurting innocent people
哪怕以伤害无辜为代价
In that case
在这种情况下
The only person I can save is you
我唯一能拯救的人就是你
more importantly
更重要的是
Even if you use the reason just now to excuse yourself
即使你用刚才的理由来为自己开脱
Luo Guanqun wouldn't believe it either
罗冠群也不相信
Because once an agent is suspected,
因为一旦代理人被怀疑，
There is no value anymore
已经没有价值了
Then what do you want me to do?
那你要我做什么？
Do you want me to die without saving you?
你想让我死而不救你吗？
I don't blame you
我不怪你
I want to say
我想说
I can't just walk away like this
我不能就这样走开
What can you do?
你能做什么？
I remember the first time we met
我记得我们第一次见面
You just rely on the difference in gunfire
你只靠枪声的差异
You can tell which agents are there
您可以知道有哪些代理
What model of gun are you holding?
你拿着什么型号的枪？
How many bullets are left?
还剩多少子弹？
Then annihilate them one by one
然后将他们一一消灭
At that time, I thought this comrade was so awesome.
当时我就觉得这个同志真是太棒了。
A hundred times more powerful than me
比我强大一百倍
If those comrades can be saved
如果那些同志能够被拯救的话
If you can successfully infiltrate
如果你能成功潜入
mission accomplished
任务完成
I'm willing to sacrifice everything
我愿意牺牲一切
including my life
包括我的生活
you must cooperate with me
你必须跟我合作
This is an order
这是一个订单
I must let Zhao An's people catch me
我一定要让赵安的人抓住我
wake up
醒来
What on earth do you do?
你到底是做什么的？
It's the Communist Party
这是共产党
Communist Party
共产党
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Just as I expected
正如我所料
It's smoke
是烟
smoke soil
烟土
You really are selling cigarettes?
你真的是卖烟的吗？
Go to Lao Lu's house
去老鲁家
Bring me the Lao Lu family
把老鲁一家带过来
yes
是的
Not Zhao An
不是赵安
It's Luo Guanqun
It's Luo Guanqun
Luo Guanqun
Luo Guanqun
The story is like this
故事是这样的
I go to the teahouse
我去茶馆
In the process of going
去的过程中
I happened to encounter Zhao An following you.
正好遇见赵安跟着你。
And Zhao An just arrested Lao Tian before
而赵安之前刚刚抓捕了老田
This CCP element
这个中共分子
So he's following you again
所以他又开始关注你了
I suspect that you and Lao Tian are both members of the Chinese Communist Party
我怀疑你和老田都是中共党员
But I don’t want you to fall into Zhao An’s hands
但我不想让你落入赵安手中
So you take me out of the teahouse
所以你带我走出茶馆
Just to get rid of Zhao An
就是为了除掉赵安
And let Luo Guanqun catch me
还让罗冠群来抓我
right
正确的
This is why
这就是为什么
The reason why I desperately want to get rid of Chen Shugan
我之所以拼命想除掉陈树干
Then why don't you just arrest me?
那你为什么不直接逮捕我？
Leave it to Luo Guanqun
交给罗冠群吧
I'm afraid you have a gun
我担心你有枪
I dare not act rashly
我不敢轻举妄动
After letting you go, I contacted Luo Guanqun
放你走后，我联系了罗冠群
Let him support me
让他支持我
Wait until the large spoon appears
等到大勺子出现
Catch you again
再次抓住你
Then me
然后是我
where should it be
应该在哪里
Caught by you
被你抓住了
Grand Guangming Cinema
光明大电影院
I'll have a large spoon appear around there
我会在周围出现一个大勺子
And you also happened to appear in front of the cinema
而你也恰好出现在电影院门口
The big horse spoon can catch you easily
大马勺轻松抓住你
But you must remember
但你一定要记住
Don’t let Chen Shugan discover you
别让陈树干发现你
I know
我知道
I'm like being caught by two eagles
我就像被两只老鹰叼住一样
Staring chick
盯着小鸡
It can only fall into your mouth
只能掉进嘴里
right
正确的
But the old road
但老路
Getting caught is just the first step
被抓只是第一步
Next you will rebel
接下来你会叛逆
mutiny
兵变
You just rebelled
你刚刚叛逆了
Only then can we save those comrades
只有这样我们才能拯救那些同志
But how could Luo Guanqun believe that I was rebellious?
但罗冠群怎么会相信我叛逆呢？
He won't believe you easily
他不会轻易相信你
So let him think
所以让他想想
He found your most fatal weakness
他发现了你最致命的弱点
what weakness
什么弱点
family
家庭
you know my family
你认识我的家人
I know
我知道
At the same time that the big horse spoon takes you away
大马勺带你走的同时
I will forge some letters and documents
我会伪造一些信件和文件
do not worry
不用担心
Is anyone caught?
有人被抓到了吗？
There is no one at Lao Lu’s house.
老鲁家里没人。
Is his wife and child supposed to be dead?
他的妻子和孩子应该死了吗？
What
什么
died
死了
yes
是的
he he he
呵呵呵呵
Although his house is kept clean
虽然他的房子保持得很干净
But it feels like years
但感觉就像是岁月
No one lives there anymore
那里已经没有人住了
I also found a photo
我还找到了一张照片
It’s a photo of Lao Lu and his wife and children
这是老鲁和老婆孩子的照片
Then there was an incense burner next to the photo.
然后照片旁边有一个香炉。
There are also some offerings
还有一些优惠
Buy these things on this old road
在这条老路上买这些东西
It doesn’t seem like it was really given to his family.
看起来不像是真的送给家人的。
It was used as a memorial
它被用作纪念
Once Luo Guanqun thinks you have rebelled,
一旦罗冠群认为你叛逆了，
He will ask you to identify him
他会要求你确认他的身份
several other comrades
其他几位同志
At this time you can only identify other people
这时候你只能识别其他人
Only in this way can we ensure the safe evacuation of our comrades
只有这样才能保证战友安全撤离
How is that possible?
这怎么可能？
Wouldn’t it hurt innocent people?
不会伤及无辜吗？
Won't hurt innocent people
不会伤害无辜的人
I have a friend who is a detective in the concession
我有一个朋友是租界的侦探
I've seen him there
我在那里见过他
Files of some ex-convicts
一些刑满释放人员的档案
I couldn't find you when I arrived at the teahouse
到了茶馆却找不到你
When I'm looking for you everywhere
当我到处寻找你的时候
It happens to be in Dongli Hall on the second floor
正好在二楼东丽厅
you remember
你记得
It's the Dongli Hall on the second floor. There are two people there.
就是二楼的东丽殿。那里有两个人。
These two people were previously members of the Avenue Government
这两个人以前都是大道政府的成员
Tobacco resale in public sales offices in Shanghai
上海公共销售处转售烟草
But later the tobacco was taken over by the Japanese
但后来烟草被日本人接管了
After monopolizing
垄断后
They started the human trafficking business again
他们又开始贩卖人口的生意
And he has several lives on his hands
他手上还有好几条人命
A heinous crime
令人发指的罪行
But those two drug dealers
但这两个毒贩
It’s impossible to admit that you are the CCP
承认自己是CCP是不可能的
Do not worry
不用担心
Luo Guanqun has many ways to make them admit it
罗冠群有很多办法让他们承认
Luo Guanqun will discover the flaw sooner or later
罗冠群迟早会发现破绽
right
正确的
this is the key
这是关键
When Luo Guanqun found out you were cheating on him
当罗冠群发现你出轨的时候
He will hate you to the core
他会恨你入骨
He will use the most cruel means to destroy you
他会用最残忍的手段来毁灭你
torture you
折磨你
Make your life worse than death
让你的生不如死
Scared me
吓死我了
OK
好的
Just do it
去做就对了
communist
共产
I'm not afraid of intimidation
我不怕恐吓
Yumo calligraphy and painting shop
玉墨书画店
Found under the floor
在地板下发现的
Is it valuable?
有价值吗？
I do not know
我不知道
You have to see it
你必须看到它
We have all been deceived by this old way.
我们都被这种古老的方式所欺骗了。
Can those tea drinkers be captured again?
那些喝茶的人还能再被抓起来吗？
How about a new trial?
新的尝试怎么样？
The address is saved
地址已保存
What do you think about the CCP?
你对中共有何看法？
Will you give us real information?
你能给我们真实的信息吗？
Blame me
都怪我吧
These forged letters
这些伪造的信件
The documents were cheated
文件被骗了
I really thought he had family in Shanghai
我真的以为他在上海有家人
We were careless
我们不小心
I should have sent someone to his house long ago
我早就该派人去他家了
large spoon
大勺子
Boss Lu
卢老板
Who are you lying to? You shouldn't lie to us?
你在骗谁？你不应该对我们撒谎吗？
How much business have Manager Luo and I taken care of for you?
我和罗经理帮您处理了多少生意？
Section Chief Chen
陈科长
rabbit shoulder purple hair
兔肩紫毛
easy to use
便于使用
Boss Lu
卢老板
Manager Luo
Manager Luo
Flower and bird pattern pen box
花鸟图案笔盒
easy to use
便于使用
Boss Lu
卢老板
Why are you doing this?
你为什么做这个？
Open your calligraphy and painting shop
开你的字画店
Isn’t it good to live your little life?
过自己的小日子不是很好吗？
good
好的
Of course
当然
drive away the Japanese invaders
赶走日本侵略者
Root out all you traitor lackeys
铲除你们这些叛徒走狗
Such a good day
真是美好的一天
One hundred years is not enough for me
一百年对我来说还不够
I can't find anything else
我找不到其他东西
I go first
我先走
etc.
ETC。
what does it mean
这是什么意思
kill him
杀了他
Not Lao Luo
不是老罗
I'm not good at this
我不擅长这个
No more trials
没有更多的尝试
I believe you
我相信你
He won't say anything
他不会说什么
My marksmanship is not good
我的枪法不好
If you miss
如果你错过了
Don't laugh at me
别笑我
what do you mean
你是什​​么意思
I loaded the blanks
我加载了空白
He suspects that I am in the same group with him
他怀疑我和他是一个组的
I didn't say that
我没这么说
right
正确的
I'm in the same group as him
我和他在同一个组
I go to Yumo calligraphy and painting shop
我去玉墨字画店
Just to pass on information to him
只是为了向他传达信息
interconnected
互联
And today
还有今天
It's also the two of us who are in cahoots
也是我们两个同谋
Identify those two drug dealers
查明这两个毒贩的身份
For what?
为了什么？
Just for the CCP in the teahouse
只为茶馆里的中共
buy time to escape
争取时间逃跑
besides
除了
You said that the four of clubs is me
你说梅花四就是我
I am the Four of Clubs
我是梅花四